<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Yannick Grenzinger</title>
    <link>https://ygrenzinger.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yannick Grenzinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ygrenzinger.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Summary of &#39;Clean Architecture&#39; by Robert C. Martin</title>
      <link>https://ygrenzinger.github.io/posts/clean-architecture-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ygrenzinger.github.io/posts/clean-architecture-summary/</guid>
      <description>Uncle Bob, the well known author of Clean Code, is coming back to us with a new book called Clean Architecture which wants to take a larger view on how to create software.
Even if Clean Code is one of the major book around OOP and code design (mainly by presenting the SOLID principles), I was not totally impressed by the book.
Clean Architecture leaves me with the same feeling, even if it&amp;rsquo;s pushing the development world to do better, has some good stories and present robust principles to build software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of &#39;Words are windows, Introduction to nonviolent communication&#39; by Marshall Rosenberg</title>
      <link>https://ygrenzinger.github.io/posts/non-violent-communication-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ygrenzinger.github.io/posts/non-violent-communication-summary/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Words are windows&amp;rdquo; is an introduction to non violent communication (abbreviated as NVC). Marshall Rosenberg presents in this book the process that allows us to communicate more serenely with others as well as with ourselves. This mode of communication allows us to become more and more caring, authentic, and empathic with others. It can therefore be used in all interactions of everyday life: as a couple, with our children, at work &amp;hellip; NVC is proving to be a very effective way to manage conflicts, and also to better identify our own needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ygrenzinger.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ygrenzinger.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>symmathecist Sometimes coach, mentor, manager but always software engineer. I am passionate about the symmathesy of building software which is a learning system made of learning parts.
Continuous Learner After a dual degree of engineering school and Master of Science, I have mainly worked as a consultant which allowed me to learn a lot and see different projects and contexts.
I developed knowledge and, even, expertise in
 software design: clean and performant architecture, efficient testing, Domain Driven Design methodology and DevOps (I am even Kubernetes Application Developer certified :D ) programming languages from Object Oriented to Functional paradigms (See my long list of experiments with different languages on my Github repo) flow methodology (using Kanban and Lean) to deliver value in production in a continuous way keeping up with the pace of business demand.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
